The argument that feminism is no longer needed in the U.S. has been increasing in prevalence,
so let's talk about why the feminist fight is not over. This argument stems from the idea that now
in the U.S. men and women are equal under the law, and so there's nothing left for feminists to be
fighting for. And it is true that after the passage of the 19th amendment and other acts
fighting for gender equality, that the feminist movement no longer revolves around fighting for
legislative changes the way that it once did. With the advancement of legal equality in the U.S.,
the feminist movement has not disappeared, it's just evolved. Today's challenges are mostly
cultural, social, and revolve around how existing laws are implemented.
In other words, double standards and patriarchal traditions are still deeply
rooted in our culture and it's important to raise awareness about it.
With this being said, these changes to the feminist movement do complicate the
movement because what success looks like is much less tangible.
But feminism is definitely still needed. Women are still
underrepresented in leadership, victims to gender-based violence and gender pay
gaps, and don't have full access to
reproductive rights. Double standards, harsh media scrutiny,
and unattainable societal standards still hold women back today and that's why feminism is still relevant.
That's all she wrote, bye guys!